# Thomas I. Bereknyei

Mobile: 650-704-1166 Email:tomberek@gmail.com

Technical planner and developer with 10 years of experience planning operations and designing systems in both business and military settings working with researchers, engineers, operators, and end-users to create efficient and creative solutions.

- Experienced project manager as lead planner for technical and operational wargames involving multiple organizations at distributed locations.
- Proven ability to identify and implement decisive solutions with significant business and operational impact.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Exercise Director

2013 — Present

Marine Forces Cyberspace Command

Fort Meade, MD

https://github.com/tomberek
https://keybase.io/tomberek
https://tomberek.info/resume

- Manage MARFORCYBER exercise participation, scheduling, and long-term development. Transformed ad hoc scheduling into a formal multi-year exercise support plan.
- Lead planner for CYBER FLAG 15 and CYBER GUARD 15 exercises; scenario design, Command and Control construct, network/target design, logistics for 118 participants, and development of training objectives.
- Provided technical information technology expertise regarding network vulnerabilities and cyberspace threats. These exercises include the design and exploitation of full enterprise Windows environments (up to regional and national networks) as well as attack platforms and replication of public Internet services.

Senior Software Engineer 2014 — Present (part time)

ChanTable Inc. San Francisco, CA (remote)

- Part-time contractor for Copilot Labs Inc. (getcopilot.com) until acquisition by OpenTable Inc. and renewed contract to perform DevOps and developer functions: maintain servers and back-end infrastructure, plan and execute major upgrades and migrations, design a continuous integration development and production environment, develop tools and utilities for administrators, and establish a security program.
- Transitioned standalone servers into a scalable and fault-tolerant cluster architecture utilizing Amazon Web Services including; EC2, S3, RDS, IAM, Elastic Beanstalk, EMR, ElastiCache, CloudWatch, and Route 53. Primary technologies used: Python, Django, MySQL, SQLite, Apache, nginx, Docker, Jenkins, git/Github, and a liberal abuse of shell scripting.
- Performed security testing and a basic security audit of systems. Resolved critical vulnerabilities such as Heartbleed and ShellShock within 24 hours of public disclosure.

### Software Contractor

2013

## Various clients

eLance.com

Produced Scala and Haskell libraries and provided technical instruction as required by clients on an hourly basis.

- Regular expression demonstration. http://RegexPlanet.com/advanced/haskell/index.html
- SEG-Y geophysical binary data parser. <a href="https://github.com/Toeplitz/haskell">https://github.com/Toeplitz/haskell</a>
- Critical learning point was the importance of formal project specification and clear communication with clients to develop requirements. Several projects grew in scope, consuming additional time and attention.

# **Electronic Warfare Officer**

# LINKS

# **TECHNOLOGY**

Virtualization 6 years
Cloud Development 4 years
Functional Programming 6 years.
Object Oriented Programming
4 years
Java Virtual Machine 6 years.
DevOps 4 years.
Linux Administration 11 years.
Electronic Warfare 6 years

# CLEARANCE AND CERTIFICATIONS

Current Top Secret

Clearance

TS//SCI with Counterintelligence Polygraph

CISSP

2015



CEH

Certified Ethical Hacker

SharePoint Server

Microsoft SharePoint Server

Site Owner/Power User

# **E**DUCATION

University of California

Berkeley

B.S in Mechanical Engineering Minor: Electrical Engineering 2005 - 2013 and Computer Science

Berkeley, CA

Marine Tactical Electronic Warfare Squadron 4

- Flew over 900 hours in the EA-6B Prowler as an Cherry Point, NC Leadership Electronic Counter-Measures Officer with 70 combat sorties for 291.1 combat hours with multiple deployments to Operation Enduring Freedom.
- After basic training and Initially assigned to the Operations Department as a scheduler and quickly becoming the Subject Matter Expert for multiple ICAP III weapon systems and support systems. Familiarity with the systems and tactics led to an early assignment as the Electronic Warfare Department Head for Exercise Red Flag Alaska and deployment to MCAS Iwakuni, Japan. Simultaneously held collateral billets as Tactics Officer, Operational Security Officer, Classified Material Control Center Custodian, and Joint Mission Planning System Officer.
- Created a novel electronic attack technique applicable to several target sets and relying on an optimizing algorithm. Confirmed the tactic in coordination with Johns Hopkins University Jammer Technique Optimization Team and employed it in combat operations. Documented and corrected long-standing deficiencies in the tactical employment of the EA-6B by optimizing for the delivery of jamming power to a target.

# **Technical Solutions Specialist**

# Google Inc.

Mountain View, CA

- Identified and prevented fraud in Google AdSense and AdWords by both automated tools and alert systems. Investigated flagged incidents for fraudulent behavior.
- Leveraged existing machine learning algorithms such as self-organizing maps and classifying neural networks to discover novel click-fraud patterns of behavior. Revealed and terminated several multi-million dollar accounts engaged in click duplication and traffic replication.

# SKILLS

# IT Project Management

- Planned two critical infrastructure migrations while minimizing business impact Martial arts: Judo/Jiu-Jitsu and downtime.
- Operated budget and planned the participation of up to 118 personnel in multiple locations for large exercises.
- Developed logistics to maintain technical support to tactical operations during movements of personnel and equipment.

# Programming

- Maintained a Haskell graph algorithm library and web-framework extension enabling FastCGI. Contributed to web-framework security. https://www.fpcomplete.com/user/tomberek/adding-security-to-mflow. Continuing to contribute to the development of a isomorphic web framework in Haskell.
- Creating a Haskell library for opportunistic normalization for dataflows and computations.
- Currently bootstrapping a Forth variant from assembly to the Mill CPU, a statically scheduled, wide issue, in-order architecture which uses a belt of temporary values rather than registers as a computing model.

# System Administration and DevOps

- Used Linux commercially, on desktop, and personal servers since 2001. Tried RedHat, Ubuntu, Arch, (and Plan 9!) before becoming involved with NixOS due to its purely functional philosophy regarding configuration, upgrades, deterministic builds, and a mix of binary and source distribution. Currently maintain 15 packages with 100% build status.
- Supported experimental, development, continuous integration, and production environments for Copilot Labs Inc. and subsequently for OpenTable Inc.
- Experienced with virtualization, including VMWare, vSphere, XEN, QEMU, Amazon Web Services (AWS) and many public and private cloud platforms.

Training

2006

2009

Basic Officer Course Quantico, VA Naval Aviation Flight

Officer Candidate School

Designated as a Naval Flight Officer Pensacola, FL

Electronic Countermeasures Officer Training EA-6B NATOPS qualified Whidbey Island, WA S.E.R.E. Training 2005 Survival, Escape, Resistance,

> **Expeditionary Warfare** School 2014 Military planning methodology and doctrine Remote

# Misc

and Evasion

- Fluent Hungarian
- Brew homemade fruit wine
- Homemade sourdough bread